Exercise 5.9: For each of the LTL-formulas below, construct a Budd 
automaton that accepts exactly those traces that satisfy the formula:
    (1)    e V o❑ f,
    (2) Do e A Do f,
    (3) 0( e eU f).

Exercise 5.10: Write an LTL-formula that exactly describes the set of 
traces that are accepted by the Bouchi automaton shown in figure 5.9.
Explain your answer. ■




                             e A f)




  Figure 5.9: Exercise: From a Bahl Automaton to LTL

Exercise 5.15: Consider the LTL-formula = (e U 0 1) V - e. First
compute the closure Sub(0). Then apply the tableau construction to 
build the generalized Budd automaton Mo. It suffices to construct only
the reachable states. ■

Exercise 5.19: Consider a transition system with two variables xand y 
of type nat. Suppose the transitions of the system are described by the 
conditional statement
        if   x > y ) then x := x + 1 else y := x.
First, describe the transition region as a formula Trans over the 
variables x, y, x, and y'. Consider the region A given by the formula 1 
y 5. Compute the pre-image of the region A. ■

